Guide to the Marvin H. Pope Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Marvin H. Pope Papers
1916-1998
RG 135
Yale University Divinity School Library
75
(157 boxes)
The Marvin H. Pope Papers document the life and work of a prominent professor at Yale. Correspondence, notes, writings, course-related materials, collected materials, and audiovisual materials shed light on his academic work and his interactions with colleagues and students. Marvin H. Pope taught at Yale in the Department of Religious Studies and Divinity School from 1949 to 1986 and was one of the world's leading authorities on Ugarit. Pope made many contributions to biblical studies, which included helping to prepare the Revised Standard Version of the Bible and advising the National Council of Churches on the New Revised Standard Version. His scholarly output was prodigious, and he helped to bring the public's attention to the importance of Ugaritic texts in the study of the Bible. During his lifetime he published numerous scholarly articles and three major books, "El in the Ugaritic Texts" and two commentaries for the Anchor Bible Series: "Job" (1965) and "Songs of Songs" (1977). Pope is remembered for his wit, which made him a popular professor during his years at Yale..
Pope, Marvin H.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist Pope.
Biographical / Historical
1916 Marvin Hoyle Pope born in Durham, North Carolina, son of Charles and Bessie Cleveland Sorrell Pope. Born in the "Bible Belt," Pope was named after a Methodist bishop. He worked part-time in a drugstore in his early teens, an experience that sparked his interest in religion. When he wasn't busy with customers, Pope read Tom Paine, Voltaire, the Bible, and pharmacopoeia.
1938 Graduated with A.B. from Duke University
1939 Received M.A. from Duke University in Semitic languages and literature
1941-1945 Servedin the U.S. Air Force 1946 Resumed his academic work, studying archaeology with Nelson Glueck, as a fellow of the American School of Oriental Research in Jerusalem
1949 Received Ph.D. from Yale; dissertation on Ugaritic particles; joined faculty at Yale as Assistant Professor of Hebrew
1955 "El in the Ugaritic Texts" published; appointed associate professor at Yale
1959-60 Served as Director of the American School of Oriental Research in Jerusalem
1964 Appointed Professor of Semitic Languages and Literatures at Yale
1965 Commentary on Job for Anchor Bible Series published
1966-67 directed Hebrew Union College Biblical and Archaeological School in Jerusalem
1977 Commentary on Songs of Songs for Anchor Bible Series published; winner of National Religious Book Award.
1979 Death of first wife, Helen Thompson Pope; Pope named Louis M. Rabinowitz Professor of Semitic Languages and Literatures
1980 Fulbright Lecturer in Ancient Semitic Languages at the University of Aleppo, Syria
1985 Married second wife, Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist
1986 Fulbright Research Fellow at the Institute for Ugaritic Research at the University of Muenster; retired from Yale
1988 Yale Divinity School established the Marvin H. Pope Scholarship in Biblical Hebrew to honor him.
1997 Died in his church in Greenwich,CT, just after reading passages from the Bible to the congregation
Scope and Contents
This extensive collection provides a good sense Pope's academic work and his interactions with colleagues and students. The final series, Offprints and Papers by Others, is not listed in its entirety in this finding aid. The materials in this series have been entered into an Access database that is available at the Yale Divinity Library.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1948-1997, n.d.
II. Notes
III. Published Articles and Reviews, 1947-1992, n.d.
IV.. Drafts and Unpublished Writings
V. Course-related Material, 1966-1989, n.d.
VI. Collected Material, 1953-1995, n.d.
VII. Personal/Memorabilia, 1916-1998
VIII. Audiovisual Materials, 1976-1993, n.d.
IX. Offprints and Papers of Others
Bible. Old Testament -- Criticism, interpretation, etc.; Educators; Pope, Marvin H.; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1948-1997, n.d.; Series I
  - Re: Pope's article on Ugaritic ndd-ydd, 1948 (Box 1P, Folder 1)
  - Re: receipt of offprints of Pope's articles, 1951-1953 (Box 1P, Folder 2)
  - Re: responses to Pope's book entitled "El in the Ugaritic Texts"; postcard from Wm. F. Albright, 1955 (Box 1P, Folder 3)
  - General, 1956 (Box 1P, Folder 4)
  - With Wm. F. Albright re: Ralph E. Baney; background info. on Baney scandal, 1960s (Box 1P, Folder 5)
  - Re: Freedman's suggestions on Pope's "Job" manuscript; letter from Wm. F. Albright on Job and letters re: Dead Sea Scroll lectures, 1962 (Box 1P, Folder 6)
  - Re: "Rock and Scroll" lecture on the Dead Sea Scrolls, 1963 (Box 1P, Folder 7)
  - Re: Pope's banquet address for N. Carolina's 16th Annual Special Education Conference, reactions of scholars to Pope's article on Job 9:31, 1964 (Box 1P, Folder 8)
  - Re: Pope's commentary on Job for the Anchor Bible Series, 1965 (Box 1P, Folder 9)
  - Re: Anchor Bible commentary on Job, 1966 (Box 1P, Folder 10)
  - Re: proposed commentary on Song of Songs for Anchor Bible Series, 1967 (Box 1P, Folder 11)
  - Anchor Bible Song of Songs contract, 1967 March (Box 1P, Folder 12)
  - thank you letter to Dr. Seerveld, who sent Pope a copy of his work on Songs of Songs, 1968 (Box 1P, Folder 13)
  - correspondence with Keith Crim re: TEV Song of Solomon; correspondence with Encyclopedia Britannica about Ugarit, 1970 (Box 1P, Folder 14)
  - general Re: black madonna, additional correspondence with Keith Crim, misc., 1971-1972 (Box 1P, Folder 15)
  - Re: 3rd edition of Job commentary, contract for Song of Songs commentary, 1973 (Box 1P, Folder 16)
  - General, 1974 (Box 1P, Folder 17)
  - Re: recording a Job lecture on cassette and contract; canine motifs, 1975 (Box 1P, Folder 18)
  - correspondence with a scholar who used Pope's Job commentary in his translation of the book into Tamil, 1976 (Box 1P, Folder 19)
  - Re: Song of Songs commentary and Pope's objection to the book jacket produced by Doubleday, 1977 (Box 1P, Folder 20)
  - Re: Song of Songs commentary, 1978 (Box 1P, Folder 21)
  - General, 1979 (Box 1P, Folder 22)
  - letter by John Maier re: book he edited entitled The Bible in Its Literary Milieu, 1980 (Box 1P, Folder 23)
  - Re: Kuntillet 'Arjud figures; misc., 1981 (Box 1P, Folder 24)
  - General, 1982 (Box 1P, Folder 25)
  - General, 1983 (Box 1P, Folder 26)
  - letter to Yale Daily News re. situation on the West Bank; response by David Wecht to Pope's letter, 1983 (Box 1P, Folder 27)
  - letter of apology to Robert Gordis re. Pope's misrepresentation of Gordis' views on the Elihu speeches; misc., 1984 (Box 1P, Folder 28)
  - Re: NRSV, 1984-1990 (Box 1P, Folder 29)
  - Re: "Hosanna in the Highest" article, 1985 (Box 1P, Folder 30)
  - Re: Hosanna, 1986 (Box 1P, Folder 31)
  - Re: Pope's retirement party, 1986 (Box 1P, Folder 32)
  - Recommendation for a student, letter including final draft of Hosanna article, 1987 (Box 2P, Folder 33)
  - Re: new version of Song of Solomon, 1988 (Box 2P, Folder 34)
  - General, 1989 (Box 2P, Folder 35)
  - Draft of a letter to Pres. Levin re. NELC Dept. at Yale, 1990s (Box 2P, Folder 36)
  - Draft of a letter to NEH re. his project on interpreting the Ugaritic mythological poems, circa 1990s (Box 2P, Folder 37)
  - Application for a travel grant to Spain, 1990 (Box 2P, Folder 38)
  - Re: review of Willis Barnstone's The Poetics of Translation; proposed SBL session on the Songs of Songs, 1991 (Box 2P, Folder 39)
  - General, 1992 (Box 2P, Folder 40)
  - Re: article contributed to the Encyclopedia of Near Eastern Archaeology about Millar Burrows, 1992 (Box 2P, Folder 41)
  - Re: Pope's proposed manuscript, letter from Charles Grench, Executive Editor of Yale University Press, 1992 (Box 2P, Folder 42)
  - General, 1993 (Box 2P, Folder 43)
  - General corresp; letter of appreciation to Ugaritic Scholar Cyrus Gordon, 1994 (Box 2P, Folder 44)
  - General, 1995 (Box 2P, Folder 45)
  - General, 1996 (Box 2P, Folder 46)
  - Re: Pope's essay on "Adam, Edom and the Holocaust", 1997 (Box 2P, Folder 47)
  - General, 1997 (Box 2P, Folder 48)
  - Re: the W.F. Albright Institute of Archaeological Research, 1997 (Box 2P, Folder 49)
  - Drafts of correspondence to Jay Ungerherder-Mayerson and Pres. Schmidt re. Yale's NELC Dept. (Box 2P, Folder 50)
  - Letter to Rabbi Brown re. Pope's reminiscences of Nelson Glueck, n.d. (Box 2P, Folder 51)
  - Draft of a letter to Pres. Keohane of Duke Univ., n.d. (Box 2P, Folder 52)
  - Draft of a letter to John W. Olive, n.d. (Box 2P, Folder 53)
  - Re: NEH grant, n.d. (Box 2P, Folder 55)
  - Re: NEH project on "The Gods and Myths of Ancient Ugarit" (Box 2P, Folder 56)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence from different orgs. (Box 2P, Folder 57)
  - Draft of a letter to Reader's Digest re. possibilty of publishing "Hosanna", n.d. (Box 2P, Folder 58)
  - undated letter re. Pope's Job commentary (Box 2P, Folder 59)
  - samples of unusual correspondence, various dates (Box 2P, Folder 60)
- Notes, n.d.; Series II
  - Ancient Near Eastern Gods, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 61)
  - Minor gods, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 62)
  - Ancient Near Eastern Myths, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 63)
  - Ugaritic gods and Ugaritic bibliography (Box 3P, Folder 64)
  - Ugaritic mythological texts, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 65)
  - Athirat, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 66)
  - Qds vs. Amrr, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 67)
  - Asherah, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 68)
  - Asherah, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 69)
  - Asherah, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 70)
  - Mot, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 71)
  - Mot, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 72)
  - Yamm, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 73)
  - Baal, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 74-81)
  - Baal and the Sea (Box 3P, Folder 82)
  - Baal's daughters, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 83)
  - Anat, n.d. (Box 3P, Folder 84-86)
  - Yatpen, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 87)
  - Ras Shamra, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 88)
  - "The Role of Women in Ras Shamra", n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 89)
  - "Theophorous Semitic Proper Names of RS", n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 90)
  - Ras Shamra, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 91-93)
  - The Legend of King Keret (Box 4P, Folder 94-95)
  - Divine kingship, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 96)
  - Aqhat, Danel's son, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 97)
  - Elyon, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 98)
  - El, n.d (Box 4P, Folder 99-103)
  - El: language issues in translation, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 104)
  - El, n.d. (Box 4P, Folder 105-111)
  - El, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 112-115)
  - El's Abode, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 116)
  - Status of El, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 117)
  - El and Asherah (Box 5P, Folder 118)
  - Joel studies, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 119)
  - Bethel, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 120-121)
  - Goetze's "Ancient Near East", n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 122)
  - "Weeping at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 123)
  - Ugaritic, misc., n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 124)
  - Ugaritology and Ugaritic language (Box 5P, Folder 125)
  - Consonantal verbal systems in the Ugaritic language, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 126)
  - Ugaritic metaphors, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 127)
  - Image of "lifting heads" in Ugaritic poetry, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 128)
  - Ugaritic cuneiform, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 129)
  - Pope's notes on "The Cuneiform Alphabetic Texts from Ugarit, Ras Ibn Hani and Other Places" by Manfriend Dietrich, 1995 (Box 5P, Folder 130)
  - "Ugaritic Words for Study", n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 131)
  - "Cultic Items and Terms" (Box 5P, Folder 132)
  - Epithets, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 133)
  - Ugaritic religion, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 134)
  - Ugaritic excavations, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 135)
  - Pigs at Ugarit; misc., n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 136)
  - Canaanites at Ugarit, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 137)
  - "Pleonastic Waw", n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 138)
  - Dissertation materials about W, n.d. (Box 5P, Folder 139)
  - "Nouns as Apodoses of Temporal Sentences in Ugaritic", n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 140)
  - definitions of Ugaritic words; transcription of texts, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 141)
  - YW, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 142)
  - YW, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 143)
  - Lists in Ugarit, Hebrew Bible, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 144)
  - "Fundamentals of Ugaritic and Hebrew Poetry" (Box 6P, Folder 145)
  - Ugaritic and biblical linguistic parallels; "Jealous, Zealous"; "OTQ" (Box 6P, Folder 146)
  - Ugaritic texts and the Bible (Box 6P, Folder 147)
  - Parallel passages in SOS and Ugaritic texts (Box 6P, Folder 148)
  - Ugaritic, Job, SOS, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 149)
  - Text 10: notes and translation (Box 6P, Folder 150)
  - 14.1-14.3, notes, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 151)
  - Translation of IAB and I*AB (Box 6P, Folder 152)
  - SS, discovered in 1930, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 153)
  - KTR W HSS, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 154-156)
  - "DRS at Chapter IX", n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 157)
  - ZKRA, Hadad, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 158)
  - KTU 1.96: Pope's notes on article "Un conjuro ugartico contral el 'mal ojo'" by Rainey, n.d. (Box 6P, Folder 159)
  - RPUM, soldiers of Baal and Anat (Box 7P, Folder 160)
  - Other Near Eastern gods/languages; Hebrew Bible; Misc.
    - Moon, Sumerian, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 161)
    - Mar-tu, Sumerian, n.d (Box 7P, Folder 162)
    - Amurru, Sumerian, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 163)
    - Kumarbi, Babylonian, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 164)
    - Dagan, Canaanite, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 165)
    - Resep, Canaanite, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 166)
    - Arameans, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 167)
    - Snake texts, Horon, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 168)
    - Horon, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 169)
    - 'Aitar and Astarte (Box 7P, Folder 170)
    - Hurrians and Hyksos (Box 7P, Folder 171)
    - Hirih, minor Hurrian deity (Box 7P, Folder 172)
    - Sanchunyaton, Phoenician, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 173)
    - Hrsf, n.d (Box 7P, Folder 174)
    - Roggia, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 175)
    - Lamassu, Lamasstu, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 176)
    - Miscellaneous grammar, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 177)
    - Sumerian sign list and texts (Box 7P, Folder 178)
    - Sumerian grammar, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 179)
    - languages, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 180)
    - Akkadian religious texts, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 181)
    - Akkadian religious texts: "Hymn to Markduk in the Form of a Litany", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 182)
    - Akkadian religious texts, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 183)
    - Akkadian religious texts: "Processional Hymn in Honor of Ninkarraq of Isin"; "Interlinear Bilingual Table", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 184)
    - Akkadian-Babylonian-Sumerian sign list, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 185)
    - "Linguistic Problems of Akkadian Grammar", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 186)
    - Miscellaneous Akkadian materials, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 187)
    - Babylonian texts, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 188)
    - Hittite grammar, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 189)
    - "An Assyrian Law Code", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 190)
    - Ishtar, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 191)
    - questions of whether there is a vocative l in Arabic, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 192)
    - German translations of Arabic, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 193)
    - "History of the Eastern Churches", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 194)
    - Bibliography: comparative, semitic, Biblical, Near Eastern, misc., n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 195)
    - Writing direction in ancient languages, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 196)
    - Epigraphy, n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 197)
    - "Iron-Age Pottery", n.d. (Box 7P, Folder 198-200)
    - Notes on Behemoth for an unfinished article, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 201-203)
    - Death in OT, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 204)
    - Biblical word for family, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 205)
    - "ABCD-It's LMN-tal", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 206)
    - Poetic parallelism in the Bible; notes on usage of "ass" in the Bible, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 207)
    - Notes re. the difference between "ass" and "arse" in English; ass in the Bible (Box 8P, Folder 208)
    - Horses, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 209)
    - "What is a Marzeah?", notes on Hosanna, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 210)
    - "YHWH's Skirts", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 211)
    - Israel and YHWH's love affair with Israel (Box 8P, Folder 212)
    - Sacrifice, Israelite "wave and heave offerings" (Box 8P, Folder 213)
    - Hebrew verb used in Job 6:16b, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 214)
    - Job 27:23, "aliy", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 215)
    - Job 41:17 (25) (Box 8P, Folder 216)
    - "Some Garbled Mythological Allusions in The Book of Job", n.d (Box 8P, Folder 217)
    - Job and The Iliad (Box 8P, Folder 218)
    - The Iliad, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 219)
    - outline of C.G. Jung's "Answer to Job", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 220)
    - Job, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 221)
    - Excrement/murk in Job and Ugaritic texts (Box 8P, Folder 222)
    - Spittle, slime, etc., n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 223)
    - Job, misc., n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 224)
    - Connections between SOS and funerary feasts; response to criticism of "Jack" (Box 8P, Folder 225)
    - Funerary feasts, Eucharist, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 226)
    - Notes re. "Solomon on Sex" by Joseph C. Dillow, 1977 (Box 8P, Folder 227)
    - "What Will You See in the Shulamite?", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 228)
    - "Archaeological Illustrations for Solomon's Sublime Song", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 229)
    - Notes: re. AB edition of SOS, 1977 (Box 8P, Folder 230)
    - SOS, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 231)
    - Jonah, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 232)
    - Isaiah, Jeremiah, etc., n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 233)
    - "Mixed Marriage Metaphor in Ezekiel 16", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 234-235)
    - Mixed marriage metaphor in Bible; femininity in Bible, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 236)
    - "Bible Sexism", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 237)
    - "Battle of Sexes" and other topics (Box 8P, Folder 238)
    - Deuteronomy, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 239)
    - Religion of the Hyksos, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 240)
    - Amorites, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 241)
    - Phonology, faulty stichometry in the Hebrew Bible, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 242)
    - "Nouns as Apodoses", n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 243)
    - Translating the Bible, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 244-247)
    - Problems of Bible translation; "The Towering Neck and Nose of Our Lady of the Canticle" (Box 8P, Folder 248)
    - RSV committee; inclusive language; Pope's own ideas about Bible translation, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 249)
    - Misc; Hebrew Bible; Ugaritic texts, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 250)
    - English poetry, n.d. (Box 8P, Folder 251)
    - Cyrus of Persia; Hebrew language; Jerusalem, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 252)
    - Ancient name Jerusalem, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 253)
    - Reminiscences of figures at American School in Jerusalem in 1946, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 254)
    - Amarna letters, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 255)
    - Notes on "Christian origins"; Dead Sea Scrolls bibliography; bibliography of materials in "Biblia" magazine, 1948-1957 (Box 9P, Folder 256)
    - Identification of hero and villain; significance of finds; criticism of Sommer's theory; Dead Sea Scrolls (Box 9P, Folder 257)
    - Archaeology, Herod and Qumran community; scrolls and Hebrew Bible (Box 9P, Folder 258)
    - Ebla, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 259)
    - introductory remarks before a lecture by Dr. Zeev Meshel of the Institute of Archaeology of Tel Aviv University on the subject, "Did YHWH Have a Consort?", n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 260)
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 261-264)
    - Miscellaneous notes; titles for Pope's pieces, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 265)
    - Miscellaneous notes, letter draft, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 266)
    - Holy war and warriors (Box 9P, Folder 267)
    - Notes re: racism, Zionism, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 268)
    - Notes for a sermon; notes on "holy racism"; "Zionism"; Judaism, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 269)
    - Racism, anti-semitism as a misnomer, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 270)
    - Prayer for peace and for an end to discrimination and racism (Box 9P, Folder 271)
    - Israel; impact of Vatican II on Jewish/Christian relations; newsclippings, pamphlets, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 272)
    - Offensive language; antisemitism as a misnomer; "Meditation on a Burial of a Skunk"; Nazis, Palestinians, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 273)
    - Nazi Germany, anti-semitism, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 274)
    - Highlighted copies of Mishnah Sanhedrin 4:5 in English and Hebrew (Box 9P, Folder 275)
    - notes on Israel,Palestinians, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 276)
    - Palestine, Israel, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 277)
    - Lebanon, Arab issues, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 278)
    - SBL Fireside chat and newspaper clipping (Box 9P, Folder 279)
    - Encylopedia articles re. dogs with Pope's notes in the margins, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 280)
    - Notes re. Gerry Cooke's " Kingship", n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 281)
    - "La Langue De Canaan" by E. Dhorme, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 282)
    - notes re. Encyclopedia on Glastonbury", n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 283)
    - notes re. John Swallow, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 284)
    - "NEB Bloopers," notes on the New English Bible, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 285)
    - Notes on "The Sacred Marriage Rite" by Samuel Noah Kramer, 1969 (Box 9P, Folder 286)
    - Notes on "Foreign Words in the Old Testament: Their Origin and Etymology" by Maximilian Ellenbogen, 1962 (Box 9P, Folder 287)
    - Notes on "Revelation and Divination in Ndembu Ritual" by Victor Turner, 1975 (Box 9P, Folder 288)
    - Notes on Spronk Review UF 19:452-63, 1987 (Box 9P, Folder 289)
    - Notes on article by A. LeMaine, 1977 (Box 9P, Folder 290)
    - encyclopedia entry s.v. "Calf, Golden" with Pope's notes in the margins, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 291)
    - Miscellaneous notes and bibliography: general, Egyptian, China-Japan, Jewish, Arab, European, British/Irish (Box 9P, Folder 292)
    - Miscellaneous notes and bibliography (Box 9P, Folder 293)
    - list of Pope's publications: books and articles (Box 9P, Folder 294)
    - bibliography re. Brevard Childs, the canon, and SOS (Box 9P, Folder 295)
    - bibliography re. Qohelet, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 296)
    - bibliography, re. Ugaritic studies, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 297)
    - Pope's bibliography, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 298)
    - bibliography re. dogs in ancient times, dogs and gods (Box 9P, Folder 299)
    - bibliography re. biblical books with female protagonists, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 300)
    - bibliography, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 301)
    - bibliography, n.d. (Box 9P, Folder 302)
    - bibliography, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 303)
    - bibliography, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 304)
    - bibliography cards: D, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 305)
    - bibliography cards:D, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 306)
    - bibliography cards: E, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 307)
    - bibliography cards: F, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 308)
    - bibliography cards: G, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 309)
    - bibliography cards, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 310)
    - bibliography cards: A-D, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 311)
    - bibliography cards: D-F, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 312)
    - bibliography cards: G-L, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 313)
    - bibliography cards: M-P, n.d. (Box 10P, Folder 314)
    - bibliography cards: U-Z, n.d. (Box 11P, Folder 315)
    - bibliography cards re. various subjects, n.d. (Box 11P, Folder 316)
    - bibliography cards: A-L, n.d. (Box 12P, Folder 317)
    - bibliography cards: L-Z, n.d. (Box 13P, Folder 318)
- Published Articles and Reviews, 1947-1992, n.d.; Series III
  - untitled, n.d. (Box 14P, Folder 319)
  - "The Status of El at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 14P, Folder 320)
  - "Ugaritic Words with Cognates Only in Arabic", n.d. (Box 14P, Folder 321)
  - "A Note on Ugaritic ndd-ydd", 1947 (Box 14P, Folder 322)
  - "A Study of the Ugaritic Particles W, P, and M with an excursion on B, L and K," doctoral dissertation, 1949 (Box 14P, Folder 323)
  - "Ugaritic Enclitic-m", 1951 (Box 14P, Folder 324)
  - "Isaiah 34 in Relation to Isaiah 35,40-66", 1952 (Box 14P, Folder 325)
  - "Pleonastic Waw before nouns in Ugaritic and Hebrew", 1953 (Box 14P, Folder 326)
  - "The Word Shahat in Job 9:31", 1964 (Box 14P, Folder 327)
  - "Some Notes on Terminology in the Discussion of Jewish Identity", 1966 (Box 14P, Folder 328)
  - "Marginalia to M. Dahood's 'Ugaritic Hebrew Philology' ", 1966 (Box 14P, Folder 329)
  - "Marginalia to M. Dahoods' 'Ugaritic Hebrew Philology' ", 1966 (Box 14P, Folder 330)